<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>CyberAmbassadors - News</title><link href="./" rel="alternate"></link><link href="./feeds/news.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>./</id><updated>2018-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Bringing Professional Skills Training to CI - PEARC18 Birds of a Feather (BOF)</title><link href="./bringing-professional-skills-training-to-ci-pearc18-birds-of-a-feather-bof.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-25:./bringing-professional-skills-training-to-ci-pearc18-birds-of-a-feather-bof.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="right," alt="PEARC18 Logo" hspace="10" src="http://insidehpc.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/pearc18.jpg" width="20%,"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="//colbrydi.github.io/cyberambassadors"&gt;CyberAmbassador&lt;/a&gt; project will be hosting a Birds of a Feather Event at the 2018 PEARC Conference. Please Join us on Wednesday, July 25th from 5pm - 6pm.  More information can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="//pearc18.conference-program.com/?page_id=10&amp;amp;id=bof122&amp;amp;sess=sess203"&gt;Link to BOF Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Description: &lt;/strong&gt;
A number of professional skills training programs and resources have been developed …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="right," alt="PEARC18 Logo" hspace="10" src="http://insidehpc.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/pearc18.jpg" width="20%,"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="//colbrydi.github.io/cyberambassadors"&gt;CyberAmbassador&lt;/a&gt; project will be hosting a Birds of a Feather Event at the 2018 PEARC Conference. Please Join us on Wednesday, July 25th from 5pm - 6pm.  More information can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="//pearc18.conference-program.com/?page_id=10&amp;amp;id=bof122&amp;amp;sess=sess203"&gt;Link to BOF Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Description: &lt;/strong&gt;
A number of professional skills training programs and resources have been developed in recent years, in part due to the efforts of the NSF CyberTraining Initiative. The goal of this BOF is to bring these groups together and explore ways to share information and coordinate efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the integration of CI in research continues, CI Professionals find themselves tackling problems and consulting on projects that are increasingly complex and collaborative. In order to respond to these various requests, CI Professionals need both the expertise to solve computational challenges and the professional skills to work effectively with individuals and teams who have diverse backgrounds, experiences, and goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organizers of this BOF will facilitate conversations and brainstorming activities within this interactive session, with the goal of identifying opportunities to build on each other’s success and develop ongoing collaborations. For example, authors of open-source professional skills curricula might meet experienced facilitators with an interest in bringing their content to new audiences. Or content developers might identify gaps in available resources and develop new partnerships to address these needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This BOF is proposed by a team that has received NSF CyberTraining funds to develop open-source, professional skills training in communication, teamwork and leadership for CI Professionals along with a “train the trainers” module to facilitate national access to these materials.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Presentations"></category></entry><entry><title>First Pilot CyberAmbassador Workshop</title><link href="./first-pilot-cyberambassador-workshop.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-05-22:./first-pilot-cyberambassador-workshop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The CyberAmbassadors project held its first workshop on Tuesday, May 22, 2018. The session was scheduled for 10:00 am - 5:00 pm in a seminar room of the Computational Mathematics Science and Engineering (CMSE) department at Michigan State University (MSU), with provided lunch and snacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two major …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The CyberAmbassadors project held its first workshop on Tuesday, May 22, 2018. The session was scheduled for 10:00 am - 5:00 pm in a seminar room of the Computational Mathematics Science and Engineering (CMSE) department at Michigan State University (MSU), with provided lunch and snacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two major goals of this workshop: 1) test out some of the new curriculum to see how well it works with a small audience and 2) test out surveys for evaluating learning and effectiveness of the materials.  Both goals are intended to just be pilot studies to help us iterate.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please email the Co-PIs listed in the 'contact' page of this website to ask about future workshops or provide suggestions!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Presentations"></category><category term="Workshops"></category></entry><entry><title>Campus Champion Lighting Talk at SC17</title><link href="./campus-champion-lighting-talk-at-sc17.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-11-13:./campus-champion-lighting-talk-at-sc17.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.xsede.org/community-engagement/campus-champions"&gt;XSEDE Campus Champions&lt;/a&gt; meet every year at the SuperComputing Conference.  During this year's meeting they had a "lighting talk" section as an opportunity to share projects going on in the CI community.  Dirk gave a quick talk about the need for communication training for CI professionals.  We also reached …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.xsede.org/community-engagement/campus-champions"&gt;XSEDE Campus Champions&lt;/a&gt; meet every year at the SuperComputing Conference.  During this year's meeting they had a "lighting talk" section as an opportunity to share projects going on in the CI community.  Dirk gave a quick talk about the need for communication training for CI professionals.  We also reached out to the experts at this meeting to see if they had any stories we could use to help ground some of the exercises we are developing as part of the CyberAmbassador curriculum.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants where pointed to the following google doc to include their own stories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdGaK5lxoLvRAn4yTXuUQiT2aGCyq49GoVd6ARPaNBDSfRncg/viewform"&gt;Share your CI Facilitation Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far we only had a handful of stories. What we lacked in quantity was made up by quality.  Most if not all of the stories have been drafted into CyberAmbassador exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thank you Campus Champions!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="Presentations"></category></entry><entry><title>ACI-REF Virtual Residency Talk</title><link href="./aci-ref-virtual-residency-talk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-08-02:./aci-ref-virtual-residency-talk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Advanced Cyberinfrastructure Research and Education Facilitator (ACI-REF) Virtual Residency workshop 2017 is intended for individuals who are responsible for helping researchers with computational and data-intensive research how to be more effective at demonstrating how to use cyberinfrastructure resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="//www.oscer.ou.edu/acirefvirtres2017.php"&gt;ACI-REF Virtual Residency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop is an amazing resource for CI …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Advanced Cyberinfrastructure Research and Education Facilitator (ACI-REF) Virtual Residency workshop 2017 is intended for individuals who are responsible for helping researchers with computational and data-intensive research how to be more effective at demonstrating how to use cyberinfrastructure resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="//www.oscer.ou.edu/acirefvirtres2017.php"&gt;ACI-REF Virtual Residency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop is an amazing resource for CI Facilitators trying to get a start on their campus and there were many talks/activities and is closely related to the CyberAmbassador program.  In particular the following activities overlap with the goals of the CyberAmbassador program:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="//www.oscer.ou.edu/acirefvirtres2017_talk_effectivecommunication_neeman_20170731.pdf"&gt;Effective Communication: How to Talk to Researchers about Their Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="//www.oscer.ou.edu/acirefvirtres2017_talk_effectivecommunication_neeman_20170731.pdf"&gt;How to Do an Intake Interview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="//www.oscer.ou.edu/acirefvirtres2017_talk_ciusersupport_colbry_20170803.pdf"&gt;Cyberinfrastructure User Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the week Henry Neeman also had lots of small useful communication tidbits and we had an amazing Ad-hoc talk about how to communicate effectively using email.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, just before attending the CyberAmbassador grant was funded we talked to the ACI-REF VR organizers (Henry Neman and Dana Brunson) about the grant and they found time in the schedule to let Dirk Talk with the participants.  The goal of this talk was to introduce the participants to the new CyberAmbassador program and hopefully generate some interest in participation.  Here is a link to the slides used in the talk:
- &lt;a href="//www.oscer.ou.edu/acirefvirtres2017_talk_cyberambassadors_colbry_20170802.pdf"&gt;CyberAmbassador&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;78&lt;strong&gt;+40&lt;/strong&gt; people were at the conference with &lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt; in person and 78 calling in remotely. Ad-hoc feedback seemed to indicate an excitement for the program.  Names were gathered to be added to the CyberAmbassador newsletter email list.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Presentations"></category></entry></feed>